https://www.strose.edu/campus-offices/its/about-its/policies/privacy-policy/

Military Friendly
AboutFast FactsHistory & MissionStrategic PlanCharter & AccreditationsCommunity Service & OutreachPresident’s OfficeConsumer InformationStudent AchievementCampus Map & DirectionsAdmissions & AidFirst-Year StudentsTransfer StudentsGraduate StudentsAccepted StudentsVeteran StudentsInternational StudentsVisitFinancial AidSummer ProgramsContinuing EducationRequest More InformationParents and FamiliesCounselorsAcademicsUndergraduate ProgramsGraduate ProgramsOnline ProgramsAccelerated ProgramsThe Center for Global AffairsOur Four SchoolsFacultyLibraryAcademic ResourcesRegistrarProvostStudent DevelopmentStudent SuccessStudent ActivitiesHousing, Dining, & CommutingLeadership OpportunitiesCareer CenterDiversity & InclusionSupportive ResourcesHealth, Counseling, & WellnessPolicies & Important InfoSecurityBookstoreSaint Rose BlogAthleticsOutcomesStudent AchievementAlumni StoriesInternshipsAlumniReunion 2021Golden RosesAlumni Relations StaffAlumni AssociationUpdate Your Alumni InformationAlumni BenefitsGift PlanningPhoto GalleryPresident’s NewsletterCentennialNews & MediaCampus UpdatesOffices & ResourcesCalendarGiving
SearchGatewaysStudentsAlumniParents & FamiliesFaculty & StaffCommunityLogin
Search
keywords, articles, departments, etc.
close search
Apply
Visit
Call
Request InfoHomeCampus Off…Informatio…ITS Depart…PoliciesPrivacy PolicyPrivacy & Legal Notice
NavigationMeet the TeamMission, Goals, and OutcomesPoliciesAcceptable Use PolicyAdministrative Access PolicyDigital Millenium Copyright ActSocial Media PolicyVerification of Student Identity in Online Learning PolicyDigital Media Storage PolicyDigital Signage PolicyIllegal File SharingPrivacy PolicyGDPR Consent NoticeSoftware Installation PolicyPassword PolicyBlackboard Enrollment PolicyComputer Lab PolicyCopyright PolicyCopyright Waiver of ResponsibilityComputer Account Waiver FormElectronic Systems Account Termination PolicyComputer Purchase and Support PolicyStay SecureCopyright InformationBelow is The College of Saint Rose (Saint Rose) Privacy Notice for both its website and for compliance with the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (“EU GDPR”).WebsiteWhat we collect and whySaint Rose collects information from individuals or entities when they access any Saint Rose website.  Information that is collected from accessing the website includes the contactor’s IP address, date and time of the website access, and the web pages(s) visited.  In addition, Saint Rose may also collect any information that it receives from your web browser, including browser type and version, and operating system.  This information helps us understand aggregate uses of our site, track usage trends and improve our services. This information may be collected through third-party vendors such as Google Analytics or Facebook.CookiesCookies are files that many websites transfer to users’ web browsers to enable the site to deliver personalized services or to provide persistent authentication. The information contained in a cookie typically includes information collected automatically by the web server and/or information provided voluntarily by the user.  Saint Rose’s website uses persistent cookies in conjunction with a third party technology partner to analyze search engine usage and web traffic patterns. This information is used in the aggregate to monitor and enhance our web pages. It is not used to track the usage patterns of individual users.
This information may be collected through third-party vendors such as Google Analytics or Facebook.Sharing your informationWe will not share your information with third parties except:as required by law;as necessary to protect Saint Rose interests; and/orwith service providers acting on our behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the data.Links to other websitesSaint Rose’s website may contain links to other unaffiliated websites. Saint Rose is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of other sites for assurance that their practices safeguard your privacy.Legal NoticeNotwithstanding any language to the contrary, nothing contained herein constitutes nor is intended to constitute an offer, inducement, promise, or contract of any kind. The data contained herein is for informational purposes only and is not represented to be error free. Any links to non-Saint Rose information are provided as a courtesy. They are not intended to nor do they constitute an endorsement by the Saint Rose of the linked materials.Additional European Union General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) Privacy NoticeIn addition to the information provided above in the general Privacy Notice, the following information is being provided pursuant to the EU GDPR:Lawful Basis for Collecting and Processing of Personal DataSaint Rose is an institution of higher education. In order for Saint Rose to educate its students both in class and on-line, engage in research, and provide other services, it is essential, necessary, and lawful for Saint Rose to collect, process, use, and maintain data of its students, employees, applicants, research subjects, and others involved in its educational, research, and other programs. The lawful bases include, without limitation, admission; registration; delivery of classroom, on-line, and study abroad education; grades; communications; employment, applied research; development, including fundraising; program analysis for improvements; and records retention. Examples of data that Saint Rose may need to collect in connection with the lawful bases are: name, email address, IP address, physical address or other location identifier, photos, as well as some sensitive personal data obtained with prior consent, when possible.Most of Saint Rose’s collection and processing of personal data will fall under the following categories:Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Saint Rose or third parties in providing education, employment, research and development, community programs.Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract. This lawful basis pertains primarily but not exclusively to research contracts.Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Saint Rose is subject.The data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.  This lawful basis pertains primarily but not exclusively to the protection of research subjects, providing medical and mental health services.There will be some instances where the collection and processing of personal data will be pursuant to other lawful bases.Types of Personal Data collected and whySaint Rose collects a variety of personal and sensitive data to meet one of its lawful bases, as referenced above. Most often the data is used for academic admissions, enrollment, educational programs, job hiring, participation in research, development and community outreach. Data typically includes name, address, transcripts, work history, information for payroll, research subject information, medical and health information (for student health services, or travel), and donations. If you have specific questions regarding the collection and use of your personal data, please contact Saint Rose’s Data Controller at DataController@strose.edu.If anyone refuses to provide personal data that is required by Saint Rose in connection with one of Saint Rose’s lawful bases to collect such personal data, such refusal may make it impossible for Saint Rose to provide education, employment, research or other requested services.Where Saint Rose gets Personal and Sensitive Personal DataSaint Rose receives personal and sensitive personal data from multiple sources. Most often, Saint Rose gets this data directly from the individual or under the direction of the individual who has provided it to a third party (for example, application for admission to The College of Saint Rose through use of the Common App).Individual Rights of the Data Subject under the EU GDPRIndividual data subjects covered by Saint Rose’s EU General Data Protection Regulation Compliance Policy will be afforded the following rights:information about the controller collecting the datathe data protection officer contact informationthe purposes and legal basis/legitimate interests of the data collection/processingrecipients of the personal dataif Saint Rose intends to transfer personal data to another country or international organizationthe period the personal data will be storedthe existence of the right to access, rectify incorrect data or erase personal data, restrict or object to processing, and the right to data portabilitythe existence of the right to withdraw consent at any timethe right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (established in the EU)why the personal data are required, and possible consequences of the failure to provide the datathe existence of automated decision-making, including profilingif the collected data are going to be further processed for a purpose other than that for which it was collectedNote: Exercising of these rights is a guarantee to be afforded a process and not the guarantee of an outcome.Any data subject who wishes to exercise any of the above-mentioned rights may do so by filling such request with Saint Rose’s Data Controller at DataController@strose.edu.Security of Personal Data subject to the EU GDPRWe will not share your information with third parties except:as necessary to meet one of its lawful purposes, including but not limited to,its legitimate interest,contract compliance,pursuant to consent provided by you,as required by law;as necessary to protect Saint Rose’s interests;with service providers acting on our behalf who have agreed to protect the confidentiality of the data.
We would like to acknowledge the generosity of Georgia Institute of Technology in allowing us to utilize its materials in developing this Privacy Notice.
Request Info
Visit
ApplyThe College of Saint Rose
432 Western Avenue,
Albany,
NY
12203
1-800-637-8556FacebookInstagramTwitterYouTubeCampus Map & DirectionsOffices & ResourcesDirectoryNews & EventsEmploymentContact UsTitle IXPrivacy PolicyAccessibilityNotice of Non-DiscriminationAnnual Security ReportCopyright InfoCARES Act
xApply to Saint Rose TodayI want to be a Saint Rose...
First-Year Student
Transfer Student
Graduate Student
xVisit the Saint Rose CampusI want to be a Saint Rose...
First-Year Student
Transfer Student
Graduate Student
The College of Saint Rose
Menu
SearchMain MenuAboutBack
BackAt a GlanceBack
BackSaint Rose NeighborhoodFast FactsHistory & MissionStrategic PlanCharter & AccreditationsCommunity Service & OutreachBack
BackOffice of Community ServiceOffice of Service LearningPresident’s OfficeConsumer InformationSustainabilityCampus Map & DirectionsBack
BackParking and TransportationAdmissions & AidBack
BackFirst-Year StudentsBack
BackVisitApplyTuition & AidAcademic Opportunity Experience ProgramInternational StudentsMeet the Admissions CounselorsFirst-Year ExperienceTransfer StudentsBack
BackVisitApplyCredit TransferTuition & AidTransfer Student FAQs: Why Transfer to Saint Rose?Tau Sigma National Honor SocietyInternational StudentsMeet the Transfer TeamGraduate StudentsBack
BackGraduate ProgramsVisitApplyTuition & AidLearn More About Saint RoseInternational StudentsMeet the Graduate Admissions TeamUpcoming EventsGRE/MAT Resource GuideAccepted StudentsBack
BackFirst-Year and TransferGraduateVeteran StudentsBack
BackBenefits & ScholarshipsServices & ResourcesOur Veteran CommunityVeteran SuccessStudent Veteran FAQInternational StudentsVisitBack
BackMusic AuditionsOpen HousePersonal VisitFirst-Year VisitsTransfer VisitsGraduate Visits and EventsFinancial AidBack
BackTypes of AidSummer ProgramsBack
BackPre-College ExperienceSummer Academy for YouthUndergraduate Summer CoursesContinuing EducationBack
BackNon-Credit ProgramsRequest More InformationParentsCounselorsAcademicsBack
BackUndergraduate ProgramsBack
BackResearchUndergraduate College CatalogsExploratory ProgramUndergraduate CoursesGraduate ProgramsBack
BackGraduate College CatalogsGraduate CoursesThe Center for Global AffairsBack
BackMeet the TeamInternational Students at Saint RoseStudy AbroadOur Four SchoolsBack
BackSchool of Arts & HumanitiesSchool of BusinessSchool of EducationSchool of Mathematics & SciencesFacultyBack
BackProvisionsCollegiate CopieAcademic ResourcesBack
BackAcademic AdvisingAcademic IntegrityDivision of Student Success and EngagementBack
BackAcademic Opportunity ExperienceAcademic Success CenterFirst-Year ExperienceIntercultural LeadershipRestart Your Saint Rose EducationCenter for Student Success StaffRegistrarBack
BackRegistrationPolicies and ProceduresLiberal Education RequirementsForms, Applications and InstructionsOff-Site ProgramsCollege CatalogsAcademic CalendarRegistrar StaffLibraryProvostBack
BackHonors Convocation & May CommencementProvost Office StaffInstitutional Review BoardInterdepartmental Studies Bachelor of ArtsDirections to Administration CenterEmployment OpportunitiesDiversityNursery SchoolBack
BackTestimonialsInformation Technology ServicesBack
BackITS Department Info & StaffStudentsFaculty and EmployeesCampus StoreStudent DevelopmentBack
BackStudent ActivitiesBack
BackClubs & OrganizationsLate Knight EventsIntramural SportsCampus Poster PolicyReunion 2021Housing, Dining, & CommutingBack
BackImportant DatesCampus DiningResidence LifeCommunity ServiceBack
BackReach Out Saint RoseAlternative Break and Year End TripsCommunity Service Strategic PlanPathways ProgramsSpiritual LifeBack
BackActivities & ProgramsSpiritual Life StaffSocial JusticeWorship in the Capital DistrictPost-Graduate Volunteer OpportunitiesSidney and Beatrice Albert LectureLeadership OpportunitiesBack
BackClubs & OrganizationsIntercultural LeadershipResident AssistantsL.E.A.D. ProgramCareer CenterBack
BackStudentsAlumniEmployersFaculty, Admin, StaffParents & FamiliesPolicies & Important InfoBack
BackStudent Conduct & SafetyTitle IX & Prevention, Education ResourcesDiversity & InclusionBack
BackOffice of Intercultural LeadershipHealth, Counseling, & WellnessBack
BackHealth ServicesCounseling ServicesFitness CenterSecurityThe Saint Rose BlogAthleticsOutcomesBack
BackAlumni StoriesInternshipsAlumniBack
BackReunion 2021Back
BackWhich Alumni Are Attending?Event ScheduleGolden RosesImportant InformationLost AlumniIn MemoriamAlumni Relations StaffAlumni AssociationBack
BackMessage from Alumni Board PresidentCapital District ChapterSchenectady ChapterDistinguished AwardsMonsignor Delaney ScholarshipUpdate Your Alumni InformationAlumni BenefitsGift PlanningAlumni StoriesPhoto GalleryPresident’s NewsletterQuick LinksCalendarCampus Map & DirectionsDirectoryEmploymentNews & MediaOffices & ResourcesContact UsGivingMilitary FriendlyStudentsAlumniParents & FamiliesFaculty & StaffCommunityLoginTitle IXPrivacy PolicyAccessibilityNotice of Non-DiscriminationAnnual Security ReportCopyright InfoCARES Act
File Your FAFSA Today
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site, we will assume you have agreed to our policy.Accept & Continue
